Matt Gaskey

Web Analytics Specialist, HTML/CSS/Javascript

mattgaskey@gmail.com

Summary

I am an experienced data analyst, having built my knowledge through corpus linguistics in my masters studies, then moving on to web analytics in my current position. I am a keen problem solver and love to take on analytical challenges. I love to dig into web sites and applications to find out how information is processed, and if problems are occurring, how best to fix them.

I have a passion for knowledge and use every opportunity available to learn something new. My current role in web analytics has led to a curiosity to explore web development, and my subsequent foray into HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.

Experience

Web Content Specialist at KeepCalling

January 2015 - Present (2 years 1 month)

As a Web Content Specialist, my duties are divided into two categories:

Web Analytics - Implementation, maintainance and troubleshooting of the company's analytics systems, mainly using Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager. Integration with Advertising platforms, both Google and other major thrid-party, creating first-party customer tracking solutions and providing data analysis and support for Advertising departments. Instruction and best practices creation for Analytics and Tag Management systems.

Content Management - Planning, organization, oversight and implementation of all content changes to the company's ecommerce stores (~75 individual sites) and Android/iOS apps. Testing of new functions, services and applications. Responding to Customer Service tickets with actionable solutions and organizing their implementation with Design, PR and IT teams.

English Instructor at ETC Groupe - Media Formation

September 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 1 month)

As an English Instructor I gave individual or small group lessons to professionals on a contract basis. My students came from a wide range of backgrounds and professions including Sales, IT, Marketing, Web Design, Product Design, Retail Sales, Communications, Construction, Banking and Finance, Law and Agroindustry.

Main Responsibilities:

Auditing student proficiency level

Assessing individual needs and designing a course of study suitable to the client

Main Tasks:

Course preparation, materials research, course design

Implementation of written, spoken, and audiovisual materials targeting student needs

Adjunct Professor at Université de Lille 3

September 2013 - June 2014 (10 months)

As adjunct professor I was charged with teaching five classes per semester for first-year university students enrolled in a language-intensive program. Class sizes averaged 35 students.

Main Responsibilities:

Written Expression and Comprehension

Oral Expression and Comprehension

Grammar

Main Tasks:

Adapting semester-long course syllabus to meet the needs of large class sizes

Preparing students for standardized end-of-year tests

English Assistant at Education Nationale

October 2010 - May 2012 (1 year 8 months)

As a teaching assistant, I was responsible for aiding non-native English teachers in the public school system in primary education.

Translator at Bechtler Museum of Modern Art

July 2010 - August 2010 (2 months)

Translation of a series of French texts into English for a modern art exhibition

Sales Associate at Music & Arts

September 2007 - May 2009 (1 year 9 months)

As a retail sales assistant, I was involved in musical instrument sales and hands-on instrument repair, and was responsible for scheduling, record-keeping and teacher payments for an in-store private lesson program with 600 students.

Languages

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

French

Romanian

Portuguese

Italian

(Full professional proficiency)

(Professional working proficiency)

(Elementary proficiency)

(Elementary proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Foreign Languages

Training

Linguistics

Teaching

Lecturing

Translation

Test Preparation

French

Literature

Instructional Design

Writing

Teacher Training

Web Analytics

Content Management

HTML5

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

JavaScript

Project Management

Research

Intercultural Communication

Communication

Teaching English as a Second Language

English

Certifications

GAIQ Certification

Google August 2016 to August 2017

AdWords Search Certification

Google August 2016 to February 2017

Education

Université de Lille 3

Master's Degree, English Linguistics, 2012 - 2014

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

French Language and Literature, 2009 - 2010

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Bachelor's Degree, Philosophy, 2001 - 2005

Grade: magna cum laude

Activities and Societies: Phi Kappa Phi

Free Code Camp

Web Development, 2016 - 2017

Courses

Web Content Specialist

KeepCalling Google Analytics Masterclass

Matt Gaskey

Web Analytics Specialist, HTML/CSS/Javascript

mattgaskey@gmail.com



1 person has recommended Matt

"Matt is one of the best and most interesting students I have had at the University of NC at Charlotte. He is a learned young man and a true intellectual of the kind one rarely meets."

— Marie-Therese Noiset, taught Matt at University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Contact Matt on LinkedIn